I was in a long-term relationship and it
became apparent that I was depressed
because I wasn't I wasn't a mom and he
was on the fence of having children he
didn't want to bring another canteen
into this world he didn't know if he was
gonna be a good dad and so he we broke
up he went on to move in with a roommate
who became his wife and they are
amazingly compatible in a way that him
and I aren't and I went on to give birth
to my soulmate the person on this planet
that is here to teach me here to be me
in exactly the right ways and so not me
in exactly the right ways I could not
have planned her better if this was
Gattaca and I got to design a child I
would have broken my life she is exactly
who she was supposed to be to teach me
every lesson I'm here to learn she is
physically like a little mini-me and I
could see her beauty so obviously she's
gorgeous and so I couldn't look at her
curly hair and freckles and not love
mine I can't see her attitude and
stubbornness and not clearly see it as a
reflection of mine and when we butt
heads it's like even in the moment I can
see that damn it Hey can't you listen to
me I'm the parent and I got a child who
in no way respects Authority I'm like of
course you don't expect and respect
Authority which gene was that I should
have canceled that one out she has
taught me emotional intelligence in a
way I never had access to it but I had
enough self-awareness to know I didn't
have access to it
so I couldn't teach it to her I could
only allow it to emerge and in allowing
it to emerge when she was little and
throw a tantrum tonsure in the middle of
public I would just be present with her
I'm here for you
we'll get through this and she taught me
that going through the storm there's
peace on the other ends
that doesn't exist when you shove those
emotions down she had made me fall back
in love with femininity that I never
really I never loved it I hated the
color pink until she fell in love with
the color pink she is an artist creative
loves to dance loves to be onstage is an
extrovert like the enth degree needs to
say hi to everyone and every puppy have
a conversation with everybody and I'm
just present for her in that she can
have the interactions with people even
if it makes me uncomfortable
like I don't have the interactions with
people I have to just have my boundary I
won't sit there and stand there and talk
to strangers but I will be present while
she's talking to them we you know taught
her proper dog anacott you have to us
before you pet them find out if they're
friendly if they say no there's a reason
and how to put her hands down how to
read dog language
but because dogs I'm good with but you
as an adult
you can't pet someone's dog without
interacting with them either can she but
if I could interact with the dogs and
all the people I probably would and
she's made me step outside of my comfort
zone in my introversion so that she
could have extraversion
to like okay we'll have to make a
playdate with friends cuz that's what
you need got it even if I'm that's not
within my comfort zone that's okay I
will push myself for you of course
you're my child but also I had to learn
with where I was on my health journey
and giving birth and that whole story
which is a story in and of itself I had
to learn how to put my oxygen mask on
first that even as she being my number
one priority
I won't be there for her whole life if I
don't take care of myself if I don't
figure out if I want her to live from
her heart and be who she truly is and
let herself emerge I also have to do
that I can't be conforming and doing the
things and she showing her a bad example
what I felt was that
so we're only s 8 years into our
parenting journey because it kind of
starts when you become pregnant and I
was pregnant almost eight years ago but
and Parenthood has taught me that I
can't hold stringently to this view of
how things are gonna be birthed taught
me that I had a birth plan that went
freakin heywhy her I don't think
anything I had planned followed through
because life and my kid have their own
plan and the inter woven are interwoven
lives what she brings to my life her
perspective the things she comes up with
I could not be more in love with another
human being and she taught me that she
taught me what love really truly is then
it's not angels singing from on high you
never get pissed off by someone it's the
opposite she can trigger me all day long
she can yell I hate you in my face and
I'm never gonna lose an ounce of love
for her I have enough respect for my
parenting journey that I understand that
other people aren't meant to be on it
that both our actual parenting journey
like they're not meant to be in my life
because they don't like how I'm
parenting her but also just there's
people who choose to not be parents and
they're here to learn other things I
don't think this is for everyone but
this this person this position of being
a mom to this human being is exactly
what I'm here to do and she is what like
this world means her is herself not
because she's better than anyone but
because she's the best person of being
her she's the only one who can be her
and that comes with having me as her mom
with happy to family of two and did I
allow her to unfold and I get to be
along for that journey and I'm on my own
journey during that same time period so
this was a little bit about my parenting
journey I can't ever do it justice under
five minutes clearly it's close to seven
I couldn't do this justice talking about
it for years but it is continuing to
unfold and I'll be continuing to share
it thank you